One of the key advantages of functions is that
إحدى المزايا الرئيسية للدوال
they can help break a program down into smaller chunks.
هي أن بإمكانها مساعدتك على تجزئة برنامج ما إلى أجزاء أصغر.
This makes code easier to write and also easier to read because the pieces of your code,
يجعل هذا كتابة الكود وقراءته أسهل،
If a program needs to calculate volumes of multiple cylinders,
إن احتاج برنامج إلى حساب سعات لعدة أسطوانات،
it can call the cylinder volume function multiple times,
فيمكنه استدعاء دالة Cylinder_volume عدة مرات.
which is much cleaner than writing out the formula over and over again.
وهذا منظم أكثر من كتابة المعادلة مراراً وتكراراً.
Functions make code easier to read because they give human readable names to processes.
تسهل الدوال قراءة الكود، لأنها تعطي العمليات أسماءً مفهومة يمكن قراءتها.
While the cylinder volume formula isn't that complicated,
مع أن معادلة "cylinder_volume" ليست معقدة جداً،
it is still harder to recognize than a precisely-named function.
إلا أن تمييزها أصعب من دالة محددة الاسم.
There is an additional technique that makes functions more readable,
هنالك طريقة إضافية أخرى تجعل قراءة الدوال أسهل،
documentation strings or docstrings.
وهي سلاسل التوثيق أو docstrings.
Docstrings are a type of comment used to explain
إن سلاسل التوثيق هي نوع من التعليقات يُستخدم لشرح
the purpose of a function and how it should be used.
غاية الدالة وكيفية يجدر بنا استخدامها.
Here is a function for population density with a docstring.
هذه دالة للكثافة السكانية مع سلسلة توثيق.
Docstrings are surrounded by triple quotes.
إن سلاسل التوثيق محاطة بثلاثة علامات اقتباس.
The first line of the docstring is a brief explanation of the function's purpose.
السطر الأول من سلسلة التوثيق هو شرح ملخص لغاية الدالة.
If you feel that this is sufficient documentation,
إن كنت تشعر أن هذا توثيق كافٍ،
you can end the docstring here.
فبإمكانك إنهاء سلسلة التوثيق هنا.
Single line docstrings are perfectly acceptable.
سلاسل التوثيق التي من سطر واحد مقبولة تماماً.
If you think that the function is complicated enough to want a longer description,
إن كنت تعتقد أن الدالة معقدة بما يكفي لتتطلب وصفاً أطول،
you can add a more thorough paragraph after the one-line summary.
فيمكنك إضافة فقرة شاملة أكثر بعد الملخص الذي من سطر واحد.
The next element of a docstring is an explanation of the function's arguments.
العنصر التالي لسلسلة توثيق هو شرح لوسيطات الدالة.
Here, you list the arguments,
تقوم هنا بتعديد الوسيطات
state their purpose and what types the arguments should be.
وتحديد هدفها وأنواعها.
Finally, it's common to provide some description of the output of the function.
وأخيراً، من المعتاد تزويد بعض الشرح لمخرجات الدالة.
Every piece of the docstring is optional.
كل جزء من سلسلة التوثيق هو جزء اختياري.
However, docstrings are part of good coding practice.
لكن استخدام سلاسل التوثيق هو من ممارسات كتابة الكود المستحبّة.
They assist you and future users in understanding the code you produced.
فهي تساعدك وتساعد المستخدمين المقبلين على فهم الكود الذي قمت بكتابته.
You can read a more thorough explanation of docstring conventions in the link below.
يمكنك قراءة شرح مفصل أكثر لاستخدامات سلاسل التوثيق في الرابط في الأسفل.